Guide to the School of Nursing, Yale University, Historical Collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
School of Nursing, Yale University, Historical Collection
1890-2007
RU 1073
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
103.75
224 boxes and 1 folio
691
The collection documents the Yale School of Nursing deans, faculty, students/alumni, and programs. The collection consists of photographs, newspaper clippings, reports, minor publications, meeting minutes, presentations and research reports on nursing, audiovisual materials, and correspondence compiled by the Yale School of Nursing, the School of Nursing Alumnae/i Association, and individual faculty and staff. Major events in the school's history, deans, and faculty are particularly well documented. Students, particularly early ones, are documented in the photographs, scrapbooks, data cards, and Alumnae/i Association files.
Yale University. School of Nursing
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The collection was transferred from the School of Nursing, Yale University, 2008.
Custodial History
The collection, originally called the Yale School of Nursing Special Collection, was maintained by the Yale School of Nursing Library, which was housed in the Yale School of Nursing building. The library moved to the Harvey Cushing/John Hay Whitney Medical Library, but the Special Collection remained in the Yale School of Nursing building for several years until its transfer to Manuscripts and Archives. In the intermittent years additional materials, including a small amount of Yale School of Nursing Alumnae/i Association records and administrative records, were also housed in the Special Collections room.
Conditions Governing Access
The collection is partially restricted. Details available in Collection Contents.
Original audiovisual materials, as well as preservation and duplicating masters, may not be played. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist must pay for a use copy, which is retained by the repository. Researchers wishing to obtain an additional copy for their personal use should consult Copying Services information on the Manuscripts and Archives web site.
Original born digital files, as well as preservation masters, may not be accessed due to their fragility. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist request that they be made. Born digital files cannot be accessed remotely. System requirements include a Manuscripts and Archives computer and file viewing software
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
The collection includes documents in digital formats. See Collection Contents for details.
Biographical / Historical
The Yale School of Nursing was established in 1923 with funding from the Rockefeller Foundation. It awarded its first Bachelor of Nursing (B.N.) degree in 1926 and its first Master of Nursing (M.N.) in 1937. In 1934 the school began admitting only college graduates. An official graduate program was established in 1952. The basic program was altered in 1956 when it was expanded to prepare nurses in public health, maternal-newborn nursing, and psychiatric nursing. The Master of Nursing program was discontinued in 1956, but a Master of Science in Nursing was established. Over the years, the school evolved based on changing training needs, support from the University administration and economic conditions.
Annie W. Goodrich, one of the original founders, served as its first dean and led the school through its formative years. She was followed by several deans who were each influential in the school's development: Effie Jane Taylor (1934-1944), Elizabeth Torrey (Bixler) (1944-1959), Florence Wald (1958-1967), Margaret Arnstein (1967-1972), Donna Diers (1972-1984), and Judith Krauss (1984-1998), Catherine Gilliss (1998-2004), Katherine Jones (2004-2005) and Margaret Grey (2005- ).
Scope and Contents
The collection documents the Yale School of Nursing deans, faculty, students/alumni, and programs. The collection consists of photographs, newspaper clippings, reports, minor publications, meeting minutes, presentations and papers on nursing, audiovisual materials, and correspondence compiled and/or created by the Yale School of Nursing, the School of Nursing Alumnae/i Association, and individual faculty and staff. Major events in the school's history, deans, and faculty are particularly well documented through photographs, audiovisual recordings, newspaper and other clippings, and writings. Students, particularly early ones, are documented in the photographs, scrapbooks, data cards, and Alumnae/i Association files.
The bulk of the collection consists of photographs of deans, faculty and students/alumni and research files, which contain presentations and research reports on nursing. Yale School of Nursing's programs, curriculum, and administrative history are also documented in the small amount of administrative records present in the collection including reports, correspondence, manuals, and Alumnae/i Association files. The collection primarily documents Yale School of Nursing affiliated individuals, however, the history of nursing and nursing education in the United States is also documented.
Please note that due to a numbering error there are no folders 650-652, 1340.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged alphabetically by topic.
Due to the retention of existing filing system, a topic may fall under several headings; researchers are advised to use the keyword search function to find all instances of a topic.
Midwifery -- Study and teaching; Nursing schools; Nursing students; Nursing -- Study and teaching; Public health -- Study and teaching; Nurses; Arnstein, Margaret G.; Diers, Donna; Goodrich, Annie Warburton, 1866-; Henderson, Virginia; Krauss, Judith Belliveau; Taylor, Effie J. (Effie Jane), 1874-; Torrey, Elizabeth; Wald, Florence, 1917-2008; Yale University -- Alumni and alumnae; Yale University -- Faculty; Yale University -- Students; Yale University. School of Nursing; Yale-New Haven Hospital
- Accreditation
  - Information and schedule for National League for Nursing visitors, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Conditions Governing Access
    Restricted until January 1, 2035.
  - "Master's Program Self Study Report", 1999 (Box 1, Folder 2-3)
  - "Master's Program Self Study Report Appendices", 1999 (Box 1, Folder 4-5)
  - "Maternal-Newborn (Nurse Midwifery) Program Self Evaluation Report", 1982 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    Restricted until January 1, 2019.
  - National League for Nursing
    - Visit and report, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Report, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Yale School of Nursing self report, volume 1, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Yale School of Nursing self report, volume 2, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 10)
      Restricted until January 1, 2027.
    - "Yale University School of Nursing Report to the National League for Nursing, 1990-1991", Circa 1991 (Box 3, Folder 11-12)
  - "Self-Evaluation Report of Yale University School of Nursing," final draft, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - "Self-Evaluation Report of Yale University School of Nursing", 1972 (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Affiliates, index cards
  Restricted until January 1, 2036.
  - A-Co, Circa 1920s-1950s (Box 124)
  - Cr-Her, Circa 1920s-1950s (Box 125)
  - Hes-Mar, Circa 1920s-1950s (Box 126)
  - Mas-Sca, Circa 1920s-1950s (Box 127)
  - Sch-Z and Operating Room Course students, Circa 1920s-1950s (Box 128)
- Alumnae/i Association
  - General, Circa 1940-1983 (Box 4, Folder 15-26)
  - General, Circa 1982-1989 (Box 5, Folder 27-33)
  - Activity, news reports, 1949-1962, 1987-1990 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Alumnae
    - Frelick, Jane, copy of letter to Judith Krauss with memorabilia, 1941-1942, 1994, undated (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Alumnae Advisory Council to Yale University School of Nursing, Circa 1951-1957 (Box 6, Folder 37)
    Restricted until January 1, 2039.
  - Alumnae Day (February), Circa 1941-1971 (Box 6, Folder 38)
  - Alumnae Day (June) and Alumnae College programs, Circa 1955-1980 (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - Alumnae Day and curriculum changes, Circa 1955-1956 (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - Alumnae/i Fund, 1999-2000 (Box 6, Folder 41)
  - Alumnae/i Task Force, "Final Report of the Alumnae/i Task Force", 2003 (Box 6, Folder 42)
  - Alumnae/i Weekend
    - 1988
      - "Opening Remarks by Dean J. Krauss and Benno Schmidt, president of Yale University", 1 (Box 151)
      - "Ada Sue Hinshaw, June at the Yale School of Nursing", 1 (Box 152)
      - "Marjorie Funk, June 1988 Yale School of Nursing" (2 copies), 2 (Box 153–154)
      - "Judy Krauss (Dean) and Patricia Gibbons," Side 1 and "Madelon Baranoski," Side 2 (2 copies), 2 (Box 155–156)
    - 1989 June 8 and 9
      - "An Evening with Virginia Henderson," Virginia Henderson and Judy Krauss, 1989 June 8
        - Original, 1 (Box 191)
        - Use copy, 1 (Box 191U)
      - "State of the Hospital" by Patricia Gibbons and "State of the School," by Judy Krauss, 1989 June 9; 1 (Box 184)
    - 1990 June 8 and 9
      - "Annual meeting", 1 (Box 157)
      - "Keynote address" by Rhetaugh Dumas, 1 (Box 158)
      - "Reactor panel to R. Dumas address", 1 (Box 159)
      - "Advanced Practice, Carol Battin, Jessica Shank-Corrello, Olympia Gregory", 1 (Box 160)
      - "Prescriptive Authority, Barbara [Safeit?] and Mary Lou Welch", 1 (Box 161)
      - Keynote address by Trish Gibbons, "The Power of Primary Nursing", 1 (Box 162)
    - 1991 June 7 and 8
      - "Keynote address by Madelon Baranoski," Side 1 and "Reactor panel," Side 2, 1 (Box 163)
      - "School Based Clinics", 1 (Box 164)
    - Circa 2000-2003
      - General, Circa 2000-2003 (Box 6, Folder 43-46)
      - State of the School (Power Point presentations), Circa 2000-2003 (Box 6, Folder 47-49)
        - Digital files, 2000-2003; 10
          General note
          Contact Public Services (phone: 203 432-1735, e-mail: mssa.reference@yale.edu) for information on accessing this digital object.
  - Ballots, Circa 1940-1985 (Box 6, Folder 50)
  - Bank books, Circa 1975-1980 (Box 7, Folder 51-52)
  - Bank expense account information, Circa 1968-1985 (Box 7, Folder 53)
  - Bills, Circa 1983-1984 (Box 7, Folder 54)
  - Biographical essays by Zenia Beliavsky-Horn, Circa 1931 (Box 7, Folder 55)
  - Board, Circa 1999-2000 (Box 7, Folder 56)
  - Board meetings and Association meetings, Circa 1949-1972 (Box 7, Folder 57-61)
  - Board meetings, Association meetings, and treasurer's reports, 1973-1980 (Box 8, Folder 62-63)
    Restricted until January 1, 2040.
  - Board meetings and Association meetings, 1980-1989 (Box 8, Folder 64-65)
  - Class Files
    - Class of 1926, Circa 1926, 1973-1976, 1996-2002, undated (Box 8, Folder 66)
    - Class of 1927 - Class of 1929, Circa 1920s, 1943-1952, 1976-2003 (Box 8, Folder 67)
    - Class of 1930, Circa 1970s-2003 (Box 8, Folder 68)
    - Class of 1931
      - General, Circa 1970s-2004 (Box 8, Folder 69)
      - Letters and reports regarding members, Circa 1980-1997 (Box 8, Folder 70)
      - Reunion books, 1956, 1981 (Box 8, Folder 71)
      - Reunion correspondence among alumnae, Circa 1966-1996 (Box 9, Folder 72-73)
        Restricted until January 1, 2042.
      - Reunion information, Circa 1951-1981 (Box 9, Folder 74)
    - Class of 1932, Circa 1970s-1996 (Box 9, Folder 75)
    - Class of 1933
      - General, 1930, 1947-1955, circa 1971-1996 (Box 9, Folder 76)
      - McLean, Jean, correspondence and photographs, Circa 1931-1983 (Box 9, Folder 77)
      - "Y.S.N. Alumnae News", 1933 (Box 9, Folder 78)
    - Class of 1934, Circa 1970s-2004 (Box 9, Folder 79)
    - Class of 1935, Circa 1970s-2006 (Box 9, Folder 80)
    - Class of 1936, Circa 1940-1942, 1975-2006 (Box 9, Folder 81)
    - Class of 1937, 1934, circa 1977-2006 (Box 10, Folder 82)
      Restricted until January 1, 2043.
    - Class of 1938, Circa 1976-2006 (Box 10, Folder 83)
    - Class of 1939, Circa 1977-2006 (Box 10, Folder 84)
    - Class of 1940, Circa 1972-2007 (Box 10, Folder 85)
    - Class of 1941, Circa 1941-2007 (Box 10, Folder 86)
    - Class of 1942, 1942, circa 1977-2007 (Box 10, Folder 87)
    - Class of 1943, 1943, circa 1977-2007 (Box 10, Folder 88)
    - Class of 1944
      - General, Circa 1964-2007, undated (Box 10, Folder 89)
      - Field, Margaret (Peg), writings and accompanying letter, Circa 1940s, 1999 (Box 10, Folder 90)
    - Class of 1945, Circa 1976-2006 (Box 10, Folder 91)
    - Class of 1945W, 1944, circa 1977-2006 (Box 11, Folder 92)
    - Class of 1946, Circa 1952, 1977-2007 (Box 11, Folder 93)
    - Class of 1946W, Circa 1950-1964, 1977-2005 (Box 11, Folder 94)
    - Class of 1947
      - General, Circa 1973-2006 (Box 11, Folder 95-96)
      - Class newsletters, given by Jewel Patton in June 1997, Circa 1948-1950, 1982, 1987 (Box 11, Folder 97)
        - Oversize, Circa 1967-1977, 1992 (Box 142, Folder 1388)
    - Class of 1947W, 1946, circa 1977-2000 (Box 11, Folder 98)
    - Class of 1948
      - General, 1946-1950, Circa 1974-2006 (Box 11, Folder 99)
      - Benedict, Ruth, collection, Circa 1972-2005 (Box 12, Folder 100)
    - Class of 1949, Circa 1949, 1976-2007 (Box 12, Folder 101)
    - Class of 1950, Circa 1947-2007 (Box 12, Folder 102-103)
    - Class of 1951, Circa 1975-2007 (Box 12, Folder 104)
    - Class of 1952, Circa 1977-2006 (Box 12, Folder 105)
    - Class of 1953
      - General, Circa 1957-2006 (Box 12, Folder 106)
      - "Class of 1953 Reunion Yearbook", 2003 (Box 13, Folder 107)
        Restricted until January 1, 2083.
    - Class of 1954, Circa 1975-2007 (Box 13, Folder 108)
    - Class of 1955
      - General, Circa 1975-2006 (Box 13, Folder 109)
      - Burtt, Larice, exhibit, Circa 1995-1996 (Box 13, Folder 110)
    - Class of 1956, Circa 1975-2003 (Box 13, Folder 111)
    - Class of 1957, Circa 1975-2006 (Box 13, Folder 112)
    - Class of 1958, Circa 1969-2004 (Box 13, Folder 113)
    - Class of 1959, Circa 1977, 1993-2003 (Box 13, Folder 114)
    - Class of 1960, Circa 1977, 2005 (Box 13, Folder 115)
    - Class of 1962, Circa 1977, 1992-1996 (Box 13, Folder 116)
    - Class of 1963, Circa 1977-1999 (Box 13, Folder 117)
    - Class of 1964, Circa 1964, 1977-2004 (Box 13, Folder 118)
    - Class of 1965, Circa 1977-2004 (Box 13, Folder 119)
    - Class of 1966, Circa 1977 (Box 14, Folder 120)
    - Class of 1967, Circa 1976-1984 (Box 14, Folder 121)
    - Class of 1968, Circa 1977-1988, undated (Box 14, Folder 122)
    - Class of 1969, Circa 1977-2005 (Box 14, Folder 123)
    - Class of 1970, Circa 1970-2000 (Box 14, Folder 124)
    - Class of 1971, Circa 1976-2007 (Box 14, Folder 125)
    - Class of 1972, Circa 1975-2001 (Box 14, Folder 126)
    - Class of 1973, Circa 1977-2004 (Box 14, Folder 127)
    - Class of 1974, Circa 1977-1996 (Box 14, Folder 128)
    - Class of 1975, Circa 1975-1995 (Box 14, Folder 129)
    - Class of 1976, Circa 1977-2005 (Box 14, Folder 130)
    - Class of 1977, Circa 1974-1997 (Box 14, Folder 131)
    - Class of 1978, Circa 1978-2006 (Box 14, Folder 132)
    - Class of 1979, Circa 1979-1995 (Box 14, Folder 133)
    - Class of 1980, Circa 1978-2005 (Box 15, Folder 134)
    - Class of 1981, Circa 1978-1992 (Box 15, Folder 135)
    - Class of 1982, Circa 1979-2006 (Box 15, Folder 136)
    - Class of 1983, Circa 1980-1995 (Box 15, Folder 137)
    - Class of 1984, Circa 1981-2001 (Box 15, Folder 138)
    - Class of 1985, Circa 1982-1993 (Box 15, Folder 139)
    - Class of 1986, Circa 1986-2004 (Box 15, Folder 140)
    - Class of 1987, Circa 1984-1993, undated (Box 15, Folder 141)
    - Class of 1988, Circa 1985-2007 (Box 15, Folder 142)
    - Class of 1989, Circa 1986-2004 (Box 15, Folder 143)
    - Class of 1990, Circa 1988-2001 (Box 15, Folder 144)
    - Class of 1991
      - General, Circa 1988-2007 (Box 16, Folder 145)
      - Graduation photographs, 1991 (Box 16, Folder 146)
    - Class of 1992, Circa 1989-1999, undated (Box 16, Folder 147)
    - Class of 1993, Circa 1992-1997 (Box 16, Folder 148)
    - Class of 1994, Circa 1993-1999, undated (Box 16, Folder 149)
    - Class of 1995, Circa 1992-2006 (Box 16, Folder 150)
    - Class of 1996, Circa 1993-1997, undated (Box 16, Folder 151)
    - Class of 1997, Circa 1997-1999 (Box 16, Folder 152)
    - Class of 1998, Circa 1998-2001 (Box 16, Folder 153)
    - Class of 1999, Circa 1999-2007 (Box 16, Folder 154)
    - Class of 2000, Circa 2000 (Box 17, Folder 155)
    - Class of 2001, 2007 (Box 17, Folder 156)
    - Class of 2002, 2006 (Box 17, Folder 157)
    - Class of 2003, 2004, 2007 (Box 17, Folder 158)
    - Class of 2004, 2005-2007 (Box 17, Folder 159)
    - Class of 2005, 2006 (Box 17, Folder 160)
    - Class of 2006, 2005 (Box 17, Folder 161)
    - Class of 2007 (Box 17, Folder 162)
  - Commencement dinner, Circa 1951-1952 (Box 17, Folder 163)
  - Constitution, Circa 1942-1980 (Box 17, Folder 164)
  - Constitution and by-laws, 1985, 1997 (Box 17, Folder 165)
  - Constitution, reports, and programs, Yale University School of Nursing Alumnae/i Association and regional groups, Circa 1932-1962 (Box 17, Folder 166)
  - Correspondence with alumnae, Circa 1997-2000 (Box 17, Folder 167-169)
  - Data profiles of programs, 2002 (Box 17, Folder 170)
  - Directory
    - Classes of 1939-1958, Undated (Box 17, Folder 171)
    - Information questionnaires, Circa 1962-1972 (Box 17, Folder 172)
    - Publication of directory, Circa 1988-1990 (Box 17, Folder 173-174)
  - Distinguished Alumna Award, 1973-1998, Circa 1998 (Box 18, Folder 175)
  - Economic issues, wages, dues, 1926-1934 (Box 18, Folder 176)
  - Financial difficulties, 1935, 1954-1974 (Box 18, Folder 177)
  - Graduate surveys, 1987, undated (Box 18, Folder 178)
  - Graduates, talks to new graduates regarding the Alumnae/i Association and sample letters from the Alumnae/i Association president to new graduates, Circa 1953-1968 (Box 18, Folder 179)
  - Historical review calendar for 60th anniversary, 1984 (Box 18, Folder 180)
  - Honorary members, 1952-1954, 1978, undated (Box 18, Folder 181)
  - Ledgers, 1943-1956 (Box 129)
  - Ledgers, 1956-1984 (Box 130)
    Restricted until January 1, 2020.
  - Memories, Circa 1944-1955, 1979, 1989 (Box 18, Folder 182)
  - Memos and speech, 1939-1956, 1973-1974, 1987 (Box 18, Folder 183)
  - National alumni board by-laws, Circa 1998-2002 (Box 18, Folder 184)
  - Newsletters, Circa 1948-1978 (Box 18, Folder 185)
  - Obituaries and sympathy letters, Circa 2000-2002 (Box 18, Folder 186)
  - Officers, Circa 1946-1990 (Box 18, Folder 187)
  - Photographs, Circa 1984 (Box 18, Folder 188)
  - President's file, Circa 1939-1948 (Box 18, Folder 189-190)
  - President's letters to reunion classes, samples, 1964-1970 (Box 18, Folder 191)
  - Professional activities, Circa 1939-1953, 1975-1980 (Box 18, Folder 192)
  - Reunions
    - 1970 reunion and alumnae events, Circa 1969-1970 (Box 18, Folder 193)
    - 1971 reunion, Circa 1970-1971 (Box 18, Folder 194)
    - 1972 reunion, Circa 1971-1972 (Box 18, Folder 195)
    - 25th reunion, class of 1931 and class of 1949, 1956,1974 (Box 19, Folder 196)
    - 40th reunion, Class of 1951, 1991 June 6-8; 1 (Box 181)
    - 50th reunion, class of 1946W, 1996 (Box 19, Folder 197)
    - 50th reunion, class of 1947, 1997 (Box 19, Folder 198)
    - 1999 reunions, 1 (Box 182)
    - Letters and ideas for classes, Circa 1961-1971 (Box 19, Folder 199)
  - Stationary information, Circa 1953-1956, 1971 (Box 19, Folder 200)
  - Treasurer's reports, budgets, and financial reports, Circa 1945-1973 (Box 19, Folder 201)
  - Yale Medical Library, 1949, circa 1970-1973 (Box 19, Folder 202)
  - Yale Nurse, "From the Dean", Circa 1997-1999 (Box 19, Folder 203-205)
  - Yale Regional, rummage sales and bazaars, Circa 1939-1942 (Box 19, Folder 206)
  - Yale School of Medicine, Alumni Reunion Weekend, 2001, 2003 (Box 19, Folder 207-208)
- Annual report and faculty publications, 1958-1971, Circa 1963-1971 (Box 19, Folder 209-216)
- Annual report and faculty publications, 1971-1996, Circa 1972-1996 (Box 20, Folder 217-241)
- Annual report and faculty publications, 1996-1998, Circa 1997-1998 (Box 21, Folder 242-243)
- Basic program
  - Publicity, news, report regarding new program, 1974-1978 (Box 21, Folder 247)
  - Report of development and planning by Donna Diers to Dorothy Sheahan, 1978 (Box 21, Folder 248)
- Budget, Yale University School of Nursing and Yale-New Haven Hospital, Circa 1930-1946 (Box 21, Folder 251)
- Buildings
  - General, photographs, Circa 1976-1998, and undated (Box 21, Folder 252)
  - 100 Church Street South, building dedication
    - Photographs, Circa 1996 (Box 22, Folder 253)
    - "Loretta Ford, YALE SCHOOL OF NURSING Dedication, June 7th 1996", 1996 June 7; 1 (Box 165)
  - 855 Howard Avenue, photographs, Circa 1976-1990 (Box 22, Folder 254-255)
    - Oversize, Undated (Box 144, Folder 1419)
  - Medical center, Circa 1939-1956, and undated (Box 22, Folder 256)
  - Nathan Smith Hall, photograph, Undated (Box 142, Folder 1390)
  - Sterling Dormitory, photograph, Undated (Box 144, Folder 1419)
  - University, 1987-1988 calendar, Circa 1987 (Box 22, Folder 257)
  - Yale-New Haven Hospital, Circa 1920, 1939, 1954, 1962, and undated (Box 22, Folder 258)
  - Yale University School of Nursing related, 1942-1944, 1990-1996 (Box 22, Folder 259)
- Clinical data 1949-1950 (Box 22, Folder 260)
- Clinical instruction
  - Nursing procedure manual, Circa 1939-1940 (Box 22, Folder 261)
  - Nursing procedure manual, Circa 1954-1956 (Box 23, Folder 262-263)
  - Students at bedside, photographs, Circa 1930s-1940s (Box 23, Folder 264-265)
- Commencement
  - Photographs, Circa 1942-1979 (Box 23, Folder 266)
    - Oversize, Undated (Box 142, Folder 1391)
  - Planning of Yale University School of Nursing activities, Circa 1938-1956 (Box 23, Folder 267)
  - Programs, Circa 1931-1946, 1975-1985 (Box 23, Folder 268)
  - University activities, Circa 1941-1951 (Box 23, Folder 269)
    - Oversize, 1936 (Box 142, Folder 1392)
- Connecticut State Nurses Association
  - Anniversary, 50th, commemorative booklet "Five Decades", 1954 (Box 23, Folder 270)
  - News, 1955, 1965, 1996 (Box 23, Folder 271)
- Connecticut Training School for Nurses
  - Commencement address by Dr. Farnam, 1926 (Box 23, Folder 272)
  - Correspondence with Japanese Nursing Society and Lippincott regarding A Handbook of Nursing, 1873, Circa 1881-1894, 1942, 1973, 1985-1986 (Box 23, Folder 273)
  - Historical sketches and 1920 catalog, Circa 1920-1950, 1975 (Box 23, Folder 274)
  - A Manual of Nursing, publication and copyright contract, 1878 (Box 142, Folder 1393)
  - Photographs, Circa 1890-1897 (Box 23, Folder 275)
  - Photographs of Connecticut Training School for Nurses 1873 pin, Undated (Box 23, Folder 276)
  - Student diploma, handbook, 1923 annual report, Circa 1890, 1915, 1923, 1933 (Box 23, Folder 277)
- Curriculum
  - Discontinuance of basic program, 1956 (Box 23, Folder 278)
  - Extension of graduate program to 2 years, 1959 (Box 23, Folder 279)
  - New programs of study (pediatrics and public health), 1968 (Box 23, Folder 280)
  - Proposal for 3-year program, 1973 (Box 23, Folder 281)
- Deans
  - Oral histories from Jane Regan's thesis, "Social Responsibility and Yale School of Nursing"
    Scope and Contents
    The interviews concern the Yale School of Nursing's response during the Black Panther trials held in New Haven from 1969 to 1971.
    - Diers, Donna, 1997 August 14; 1 (Box 166)
    - Krauss, Judith, 1997 September 3; 1 (Box 167)
    - Wald, Florence
      - 1997 August 15, 1 (Box 168)
      - 1998 January [24?], 1 (Box 169)
  - Group photographs, Circa 1944-1948, 1972, 2001 (Box 23, Folder 282)
    - Oversize (Box 144, Folder 1420)
  - Painted portraits, photographs, Circa 1998, and undated (Box 24, Folder 283)
  - Bixler, Elizabeth, photographs, Circa 1926-1967 (Box 24, Folder 284)
  - Carmichael, Bruce, photographs, Circa 2000 (Box 24, Folder 285)
  - Diers, Donna
    - Photographs, Circa 1972-2003, and undated (Box 24, Folder 286)